Guide to the Delta Kappa Epsilon records,1870-2003.
Delta Kappa Epsilon records,1870-2003.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Delta Kappa Epsilon records, 1870-2003.
37-4-1535
Delta Kappa Epsilon.Delta Chi Chapter (Cornell University).
3.6 cubic ft.
Minutes, lists, records, photographs, typescript history,pamphlets, directories, catalogs, brochures, memorabilia, and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, membership lists, initiation records, photographs, typescript narrative history, pamphlets, directories, catalogs, brochures, and memorabilia of Delta Kappa Epsilon.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, membership lists, initiation records, photographs, typescript narrative history, pamphlets, directories, catalogs, brochures, and memorabilia of Delta Kappa Epsilon. Includes fund raising correspondence and other papers of Walter Bruske concerning Delta Kappa Epsilon at Cornell University; petition from H. William Fogle, Alumni Secretary to the New York State Dept. of Environmental Conservation to place two Norway spruce on the New York State Famous and Historic Trees Register, 1987; and petition from the Delta Chi Association to the National Register of Historic Places. Also, "The Delta Chi Deke" newsletter, 1935-1991; 1988 Pledge Class DKE history project research tasks binder; and report of the Alumni Historian, 1988. Also, an 1870 Cornellian listing Delta Upsilon as an "Anti-Secret Society." Includes an 1870 Charter, and a 1908 replacement charter. THE CORNELL DEKE HOUSE by William Fogle. Also a recording of the Muskrat Ramblers Dixieland Jazz Band performing at the DKE house at Spring Weekend in May 1967.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Delta Kappa Epsilon.; Bruska, Walter.; Fogle, H. William.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Chapter minutes since 1936 require written permission of President of Delta Chi Chapter, Delta Kappa Epsilon for access and reproduction. Boxes 3, 6, 13, 21, are restricted.
Some files and additional information are available online in ecommons here: http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/3223.
A copy of the detailed box list is available by clicking here. (5 MB Searchable PDF)
CONTAINER LIST
- See above link for the most up to date box listing. Includes item level listings not included below.
- Books, Bound, DKE Personal Record Blanks. (Box 1)
- Uncataloged material. (Box 2)
- Books, Bound, DX Chapter Meeting Minutes (CMM). Newsletters, The Delta Chi Deke. (Box 3)
  Restricted
- Books, Bound. Directories, Membership. Newsletters, The Delta Chi Deke. Reports. (Box 4)
- Artifacts. Artworks. Photographs, DKE Convention Attendees. Photographs, Artifact. Photographs, Brotherhood Assembled, Yearbook. Photographs, Brotherhood Assembled. Photographs, Deke House Exterior. Photographs, Deke House Interior. Photographs, Deke House Party. Photographs, Individual Portrait. Photographs. Photographic Composite, Annual. Postcards. (Box 5)
- Books, Bound, DX Chapter Meeting Minutes (CMM). Books, Bound. (Box 6)
- Artifacts. (Box 7)
- Books, Bound, DKE Songs. Books, Bound, Record. Books. Photographs, Deke House Exterior. Photographs, Deke House Interior. Photographs, Brotherhood Assembled. Also, uncatalogued petitions concerning the lodge, early versions of published studies, heraldry papers, digital data diskettes for the DKE History Program circa 1991, photographic color slides and B&W negatives. Color Slides: DKE1-054, -063, -064, -065, -073, -077. DKE2-002, -006, -007, -008, -009, -010, -011, -012, -013, -014, -018, -019, -020, -021, -022, -023, -024, -025, -026, -027, -028, -029, -030, -031, -032, -033, -034, -035, -036, -037, -038, -039, -040 and -041. (Box 8)
- Photographs, Deke House Exterior. Photographs, Deke House Interior. Photographs, Deke House Interior. Uncataloged photographs and scrapbook pages. (Box 9)
- Booklets. Directories, Membership. Newsletters, The Delta Chi Deke. (Box 10)
- Artifacts. (Box 11)
- Booklets. Documents. Documents, Photocopy. Drawings, Architectural Plan. Magazines. Photographic Composites, Annual. Posters. (Box 12)
- Artifacts. Artworks. Books, Bound, DX Chapter Meeting Minutes (CMM). Booklets, Membership Directory. Booklets, Rushing Brochure. Correspondence. Documents. Magazines. Media, Digital Data. Newsletters, The Delta Chi Deke. Photographs, Deke House Exterior. Postcards. (Box 13)
- Books. Booklets, Annual Newsletter & Directory. Booklets, Pledge Manual. Booklets, Rushing Brochure. Correspondence. Documents. Journals, The Deke Quarterly. Photographs, Deke House Interior. Photographs. (Box 14)
- Seven uncataloged photograph albums marked with temporary labels: ca. 1964, 1964-66, ca. 1980, 1980, 1993, 1995 and 1996. (Box 15)
- Booklet, Cornellian ’70 (1870). Booklets, Membership Directory. Artifacts. One uncataloged photograph album marked with temporary label, 1999-2000; one envelope labeled MISC GROUP PHOTOS, and seventeen envelopes containing annual composite photographs with labels, 1965-1966, 1964-1967, 1967, 1968-1969, 1968-1969-1971, 1976, 1976-1978-1988, 1995, 1978-1982-1992, 1982-1990-1993, 1996, 1995-1998, 1997, 1999, 1999-2001-2003, 2000 and 2001. (Box 16)
- Three uncataloged photograph albums marked with temporary labels, 1992, 1994-1995 and 1997-1998. (Box 17)
- Artifacts. (Box 18)
- Artifacts. Artworks. Booklets. Documents, Certificate. Flyers, Campaign. Media, Digital Data. Photographs, Brotherhood Assembled. Photographs, Deke House Party. Postcards. Posters, Campaign. (Box 19)
- Documents, Certificate. Documents. Map Sheets. Photographs, Artifact. Photographs, Brotherhood Assembled. Photographs, Deke House Party. Photographic Composites, Annual. (Box 20)
- Three uncataloged record books and a videotape. Record books are restricted (Box 21)
- Books, Bound, DKE Songs. Books, Record. Booklets, Membership Directory. Booklets, promotional Brochure. Booklets, Rushing Brochure. Booklets. Magazines. Media, Digital Data. Photographs. (Box 22)
- Photographs (Box Ms. Box 26, Folder 1)
  Includes photos of President Gerald Ford, George H. W. Bush, and George W. Bush, signed and inscribed to DKE. The G. W. Bush inscription congratulates DKE on their Lion Trophy.
- Oversize photographs (Box Ms. Box 52, Folder 1)
- Charters (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Replacement charter (Mapcase-folder 2)
- Digitized items, CD-78
- Muskrat Ramblers Dixieland Jazz Band recording, May 1967; tr-9503
  Use DVD-863. Recorded at the DKE house during Spring Weekend. Performers may include: Walt Koken, (banjo), H. Philip Hodes (trombone, d. 2006), Leon Oakley (cornet), John C. Bittence (bass), Jack Hockenberry (trombone), Michel Sebastiani (clarinet), John F. Geherin (drums), Roy Rubinstein (trombone), Paul Somers (piano) and Michele Sebastiani (clarinet).
- Muskrat Ramblers Dixieland Jazz Band recording, DVD-863
  Copy of tr-9503
- Time Capsule (Box T)